i can't find it. why don't i have Friends with Brews? i think i deleted the wrong one.
I haveoh here it is. Friends with Brews! Best opening ever. Best opening ever of a best week opening ever.
What a week. Whew. Well you had the best opening ever. I saw the best finale ever to the World Cup just now.
Holy moly. Yeah I think a lot of people did including I saw people posting on Mastodon.
Yeah, you know what? I almost said I saw people posting on Mastodon that they don't like soccer
It is boring and yet they thought that was the most exciting thing they've ever seen. Yeah, it was an amazing
Minus the I don't like soccer part. I do like soccer. I did enjoy one woman's comment though on Mastodon
She said if I want to see men who can't score. I'll just go read the comments on Twitter
Funny funny. Okay. Okay. Hey speaking of Mastodon
Real quick. I don't think this is gonna be a Mastodon episode. No, but what is your preferred?
Desktop Mastodon client the website. They're all I was wondering mammoth has
mammoth has
Mammoths. Oh my god, Scott mammoth. Yeah, definitely mammoth time for mammoth Wapner
Okay, let me start all over. It's been a week. And as you know, I was just waking up. We just headed to podcast
Okay, which is great you wake up on the wrong side of the bed you're exhausted you're pissy you're angry at everything
Let's record. I'm actually not this time
I was angry last week for reasons that you know why because I was really physically out of sorts
Uh-huh
No, actually I was gonna say that's the one thing it's been a week and I do feel utterly exhausted
But the one nice thing about being physically trained is my body still feels good. Like I still feel good
Mm-hmm, so I saw I'm in a good mood because that now what were you gonna talk about?
What was I gonna come in on? What was I trying to say?
Oh mammoth mammoth may not specifically be written to run on the Mac
But it runs on the Mac and I don't know if that's just because it gets the iPad it runs on the Apple silicon Mac
And I don't know if that's just because it's running the straight iPad version or if he actually is tweaking it for a Mac version
I can't remember. It's in test flight. I think it probably
Let me open test flight mammoth
It doesn't say? So I'm guessing that he just said run it on all platforms, but he's probably
not doing anything to make it specifically Mac-like. So anyway, the reason I don't use
Mammoth on the Mac is because every time I try to post something it just crashes. It just disappears.
That's a good reason to not use it on the Mac.
Yeah, on the other hand, it keeps you from saying things you'll regret later.
Well, that's also a good reason.
So I use the website and then of course on iPad and iPhone I use the ivory
Test flight beta right and I'm using that as well. I haven't done much with it
I've only posted like two things I noticed but you know, that's okay. I'm okay with that. I'm trying to get you involved more
I'm I am okay not being wedded to another social media site with me the balance like
if I am watching
security folks and I want like the latest news and stuff, then that's one thing. But
I don't need like, okay, Twitter's gone. I haven't been like actively looking at Twitter
in years. I get that. Well, I know that. Anyway. Yeah. So, so I'm not looking for something
to look at, but, but I like the things that you curate for me, Scott. You might as well
enjoy it in the good days. This is as good as Mastodon's ever going to get in terms of
Lack of a**holes.
Probably.
And on the same token, we now have the owner of Twitter over there banning journalists
and links to Mastodon.
Did you see that part?
I totally missed that a couple days ago.
Yeah, he's not naive and well-meaning.
He's naive and very ill-intentioned.
Oh, let's talk about our brews before we get any further.
Yeah, let's.
Why don't you go first?
Because I got to pick up the name again.
Today's a coffee day.
It is a coffee day.
Coffee day for me as well.
Okay, I'm having a Water Avenue, which is brewed in Portland, where I live.
Water Avenue, my goal in life by the way, Peter, is to make everyone think that that's
actually how you say Portland, and have everyone say "Portland" so that I can tell that they're
a listener to this podcast.
Portlandia.
Water Avenue, coffee company, Wonderland.
Perfect for Portland.
It's a cozy blend for misty mornings, and I gotta say it was a little misty earlier.
It's a medium roast, wonderfully balanced with festive tasting notes of, get ready for
this, baking spice, brown sugar, and toasted nuts.
Huh.
These are not your father's toasted nuts, by the way.
I couldn't have read it better myself.
Oh my god.
These are not your father's toasted nuts.
You didn't make that up, did you?
No, I did, actually.
That part I made up.
Oh, you did?
I did make up the part about these are not your father's toasted nuts.
Okay. Okay.
Seemed like it. I just am offering it up to them.
If they're listening by chance,
I want them to know that not only do we want sponsorship,
they can have that slogan for free.
Awesome. Well,
I am drinking a cup of Wegmans Dark Horizon
coffee.
That is a dark horizon. Is it an event horizon?
It's bold with, uh, with notes of dark chocolate.
It is a medium dark roast.
Now you know, normally I go all in on the dark stuff, but I say dark horizon, it's distant
horizon.
Did I say distant?
It's distant, distant horizon.
Distant event horizon.
There's no event in it.
It's distant horizon.
And I like it a lot.
The first time I've had it was this morning, and I am on my third cup and I have not put
anything in it.
Didn't put any cream, which I normally do.
I suspect it probably would taste even better with cream, but I wanted to just taste it
straight up and it's really nice.
From the website, bold with notes of dark chocolate,
blend of beans from Colombia, Brazil,
Ethiopia, and Nicaragua.
From crop to cup, sourced and roasted with care,
our supplier partner has direct relationships
with global coffee farmers that bring you the best
and responsibly sourced coffee from around the world.
Our food you feel good about, Yellow Banner,
is your shortcut to great tasting products
with no artificial colors, flavors, or preservatives.
Yes, these are not your father's toasted nuts.
It says nothing about your father's toasted nuts.
Okay.
Oh my god.
I'm so glad that I grew up and became an adult.
I am actually happy to report that my father is safe and sound.
So Vermont got a huge load of snow.
Giant blizzard.
Oh, oh, I thought this was back to the falling incident
No, they had a load of snow like two feet my debt by my dad's asked a snow falling incident and a couple yes
Exactly that kind of falling and a couple of years ago
I had persuaded him to put in a generator and I'm glad he has because for two days he had no power
I don't even know if he has any power now because he told me he was gonna snow blow and get out to the propane
Generator to see or to the propane tank to check the fuel level
But he's basically been running on generator power for the last two days now and it's great when I heard Adam
saying on blurring the lines that
His daughter's boyfriend I think was questioning him about why you would want
Backup stores of food like extra food supply on hand. Uh-huh. I thought to myself, you know, we do have some stuff
Stored away, but we're not as good as we could be. Mm-hmm
I'll freely admit that but to wonder why it's a good idea. Ah
Hello, I have an ex-girlfriend and this was right when covid was getting started and I was stocking up on
dried foods rice beans
Oatmeal right coffee and then other stuff that was just last forever
peanut butter speaking of toasted nuts
Cans of tuna canned vegetables and she was like, why would you why would you get canned vegetables?
We can get fresh and I was like, you don't
Get it. Do you this isn't about the quality of the eating experience?
Exactly. This was like, you know
I want to make sure I have something to eat and I'm gonna worry about how tasty and healthy it is later right now
Honestly, I'm looking for calories
Let me live first. Let me stay alive for a little while and then I'll worry about the fine dining experience
Uh-huh
Exactly. Was that the end? Was that the day you broke up there? It came shortly after actually
It wasn't that wasn't the day but it was it was it was it was it was that day adjacent
Anyway, so so you we both I think we have two thumbs up for our coffees. Is that safe to say?
Yeah, I think so. I think every time I have a coffee that I haven't tried before,
there's a little experimentation before I get the brewing of it exactly right.
And to be honest, I'm very non-scientific. I'm scientific about my baseline brew.
But I'm very non-scientific about what changes I make, and I can't even tell you what they are.
I just kind of go by feel, and then it turns out better, and I'm like,
"Hey, this coffee's better than I thought because I brewed it right this time."
So I think so. Right now, this one's a tiny bit bitterer than I would like,
but my assumption is that I just need a few less... I need less grams of beans for this one compared
to other ones maybe, and I think it would be really good. I think if I just dropped a couple
grams of beans off the list and maybe... yeah, probably that was the biggest thing. Cool,
all right. I don't change a whole lot else. So, it is Sunday, but I do have things going on today,
so let's stay on track. I'm not bailing on you, but I am trying to keep us focused. So,
So what else is next? Talk to me about the Google Drive user interface.
Yeah, I think I lost a follower on Mastodon because I was saying that Google has never
been able to design a UI to save their lives because I think they just fundamentally don't
understand human beings, which I think is a fair assessment.
Have you used Microsoft OneDrive or SharePoint? Yeah.
Have you used SharePoint? Yeah, I've used SharePoint. I hate SharePoint.
Okay. I mean, I not just calm yourself. I can see your blood pressure.
So I can see your pulse already pulsing through your ATP cat. Just calm down,
calm down, calm down. No, in all seriousness, what I'm saying is I agree with you.
Google drives, UI is a little bit crap,
but then I compare it to one of those times when I have to use SharePoint and
I'm like, Oh my God, this is so much worse.
But at least with SharePoint, if you say add a document, it says, Oh,
we're in a certain folder.
Maybe I should add that document here and it adds it there.
Google Drive, you make a copy of an existing document
that's in the friends with beer folder.
Which is the folder that I share with you?
So that you can see it.
Yeah.
Now, if I just make a copy of our template
and I start making show notes for today,
do you think Peter Nikolaidis is going to be able to see it?
No, because it doesn't put it in the same drive.
It doesn't put it in the friends with beer folder.
it puts it up in my personal drive in the root directory so that Peter cannot see it,
because that seems like the most logical reason I'd want to copy a file is to move it the hell away,
not to change it slightly. It makes perfect sense. Why, Peter? They're the only one that do that,
as far as I know. Yeah, I cannot tell you why that would happen. And then at least when you go to
SharePoint as slow and abominable and horrible as it is, it presents you with the stuff that
the people want to be in each view. You get there, there's some links, there's some folders,
blah blah blah, you go into the folders, the stuff is there, nothing moves around. You
go to drive.google.com and it says, "I'm going to show them a dashboard of the amazing things
that they don't know exists." Yeah, not only do I not know they exist, I don't want to
know they exist. I'm looking for my folder. I don't care about all that other stuff that
somebody shared with me five billion years ago. I don't care about the wallpaper that some idiot
put in Google Drive instead of posting on a website. I don't want it. I want my friends
with beer folder. Show me that. How about show me the folders? They're directly in my...
So let me play Google's advocate here for a second.
Oh my god, you ass.
one person could argue, and this is hilarious, right?
That what they're doing is more privacy.
I can't even stay with the straight face.
By hiding your own stuff from you?
Well, no, hiding it so that hiding it so that I don't get,
so you make a copy of it and I don't see the copy by default.
That part of it. Yeah. Yeah. Right. So you get to make your copy,
but just in case you didn't want to overshare.
Okay.
then what I need to do is test to see if that is the same way in non-shared folders
because if it does the same thing with a non-shared folder then that is wrong.
But that's a point that I never thought of.
So let me go to my drive.
Yep, I'm going to make a new folder.
New folder.
I'm going to make a test.
Testing.
Yes, Google is very testing.
Now I'm going to make a new document.
Okay, so I go to untitled documents.
So where does it, oh, I see what the problem is.
The problem is that Google Drive and Google Docs
want to be two separate things.
Hmm.
And so now when I say, hi, that's the name of my document,
saved to Drive, so now I want to go back to Drive.
Oh, it did save it in testing.
Okay, you know what?
Good troubleshooting.
You're the software tester today, not me.
That is exactly what Google's doing.
Believe me, when it comes to software, I can be testing.
Oh, you're very testing.
I am testing.
I can be trying, too.
But see, normally I think of all the weird test cases.
I didn't even think about the fact
that because it was a shared folder--
yeah.
OK.
Good to know.
You're welcome.
Brilliant.
Thank you.
Wow.
Wait, I want you to mark this down.
Scott Wilsey is admiring Peter Nikolaidis' technical skills
today.
What?
Yeah, OK.
Thanks.
I thought it was a nice thing.
Ah.
Okay, so we solved that mystery. That's actually-
Yay! You're welcome.
Alright, people.
So, Peter is your, uh, consultant.
Oh, man.
Oh, oh, oh.
I, uh, just-
Last night, I forgot to tell you.
I got a, uh, an email from, uh, our friends over at Meta
asking if, um, I wanted to, uh, interview for their security engineering team.
[Gasp]
Oh my god. Are you serious?
Mm-hmm.
And you said, "No, you're holding out to be on Twitter's security team?"
I might just do that. I might just do that. That'd be awesome. Oh, man.
I have not responded. Anyway.
That's okay. That's very minimal.
Carry on. Yeah, carry on.
Maybe you could get the goggles. You could be a virtual world security guy. You could
bumble around as an avatar typing cookie.
Type cookie, you idiot.
[laughter]
Oh boy.
Okay, so you and I both use rectangle.
And I believe that you have paid for it by now? Or not?
I have to check. I meant to.
It's a separate download.
I know, I know. Let me just check.
About... I was gonna say, if you haven't downloaded something separate...
I have not yet purchased the Pro.
Nope, I'm still running just plain old rectangle.
I did at one point get as far as going to the website, and then...
I got distracted somehow.
somehow. I'm also drinking a Gatorade Zero which I'm not going to put in the
show notes or in the brews sections. Not technically a brew so... It's a chemical
disguised as a sports drink. Okay well what I wanted to talk about with
rectangle is it definitely solves some problems that I feel like Apple should
have solved themselves. Okay. Basic window management that you know Apple should
have thought of. Stage manager is not the answer and I know that some people like
it, happy for you. So very, very happy for you. Not sharing that opinion. And I have
reasons why, but we're not here to talk about Stage Manager. If anyone feeds back at us
and says, "Oh my God, Stage Manager, amazing, lolz. I have reasons why no person with an
orderly mind would use Stage Manager." But, see how I'm not talking about Stage Manager?
Let's talk about rectangle. So what's your use case? What are the shortcuts that you
the most? What do you find the most useful about it that Mac OS doesn't have
built in natively?
Admittedly, I don't spend as much time moving back and forth
between a Windows computer keyboard and a Mac keyboard anymore. That said, I don't
like when I become overly reliant on keyboard shortcuts that I can't port
back and forth. Now my brain and thumbs have been trained so that I can use control whatever when
I'm sitting on a Windows keyboard and command whatever when I'm sitting at a Mac. That much I
can do easily. I still sometimes strip on that. But remembering like control option shift caret,
you know, whatever. Those are like, I'm never going to. So what I do is I have largely a default
rectangular rectangular rectangle configuration and I use it with the hot zones I guess they're
called when you move like the the window so if I want to take the current window I'm in
where it leaps to a certain position yeah so like I'll take this facetime window I'm looking at you
in right now and drag it to the top of my screen and it doesn't almost maximize right a zoom to
like full screen yeah yeah yeah and then I'll take it and bring it to the right edge the right or
rightmost edge and let it go there. Now you take up the right half of my screen. And if I take it
down to the bottom center of my window and let it go there, it takes up the middle third of the
screen. So those are the features that I'm using mostly. I haven't, I guess you can do like custom
layouts where you can put like this window in this special area and stuff, which I just haven't gotten
around to yet. I do that in Windows when I use PowerToys. They have, I think it's called
Zones, desktop zones, and I like that because like when I'm gaming for instance, I have a zone like
the gaming window will be here, my Discord window will be here, and a preview window with the rule
book will be here and just like snaps them all right in the perfect place and I like that.
Yeah.
Haven't gotten around to that with rectangle yet.
So I do have some, I do have a couple layouts saved.
The one thing is it requires me to have the programs already open,
but if I have those programs open and I hit that key shortcut, they will go to their places.
Now, the one thing about macOS that it is fairly good at is
those apps already remember their places, so I don't actually have to trigger that shortcut.
Right. Yep. So overall, I like it. I definitely will, you know, it's worth the $9.
Like I had mentioned this either on a previous episode of this episode of this show or was it Blurring the Lines?
I don't remember but I had mentioned that I purchased Moom from Many Tricks
Which I had heard about from John Chidgey over at the Engineered Network
Right, and then I purchased it which I had heard about from Peter Nikolaidis at the Blurring with Lines and Friends with Brews podcast
But Rectangle seemed to work better for me and it was easier for me to get started and more intuitive
So yeah, it's stuck in my brain. Yeah, it's absolutely worth, you know, the $9 or whatever to buy the pro
I should I'm just gonna do that on the podcast today, you know, that's what I'm gonna do
I think gentlemen Peter Nikolaidis is going to recite his credit card number into the microphone
Wouldn't go that far but what I will say I do have one complaint about it. Somebody's having a case of the Mondays
Where and it's only Tuesday. I mean, it's only Sunday. I mean, whatever Wow, don't rush my days off away
What I will say is one problem I have is with so I use virtual desktops and
it will and I also use my
iPad as a secondary display. Oh, oh, I've never tried that. Is that continuity? What is that called?
I think I don't remember if that's continuity. It's not universal control
Universally control is when you're controlling it but not using it as an extended display
So I just use that as an extended to so it's not universe but is it universal desktop?
I don't even remember doesn't matter. So it's literally just functioning as a display at just a display, correct?
You can do either way. You're not sliding over to it using iPad apps. It's displaying whatever's on your Mac, correct?
It's strictly just a display. That's all you're using it for. I think that's continuity display. That might be however
There's a problem with that is if I have virtual desktops
Let's just imagine I'm on my main desktop on my Mac. That's in the center
I have a virtual desktop to the right,
and I have my iPad to the left, okay?
So from left to right, I have iPad,
main display, virtual display.
If I drag a window to the far right window, boom,
rectangle snaps it to take up the right half of the screen.
No, I take that back.
I take that back.
If I drag it to the far left where the iPad is,
Rectangle will snap it to the left half of the screen if I drag it to the right side car it it
Drags to the virtual display off to the right
I move the application from the main display to the side to the secondary just virtual display
Yeah, and I can't drag it back
I have to invoke the the desktop
You know virtual desktops thing at the top with like three fingers swipe up on my trackpad
And then I have to drag it back to desktop one
Haven't gotten around to figure out if that's a configuration problem if that's a bug or whatnot. That's my one complaint about
Rectangle other than that. It's it's really cool and easily worth a few bucks
speaking of trackpad since he brought it up, I will say so I have a
What are you I have a Logitech M7 something Pro. I don't know. It's a decent mouse
Mm-hmm, and I like the mouse for the most part
But I also have a trackpad a magic trackpad sitting here on my left hand side of my keyboard and it's only there for
for those type of gestures that you're talking about okay, and
Because they're kind of magic if you remember them, they're amazing
Yeah, a lot of people don't like spaces where you maximize
You know you maximize a window really maximize not just maximize so that you can still see the menu bar and the and the dock
But it takes over the entire screen and it goes to its own separate place and you have to go sideways to get there
That's spaces, right?
The nice thing about spaces is if you use three fingers
You can swipe side to side between your apps and it is so much faster than command tabbing and finding the app in the command tab
List absolutely. Yeah, it's left swipe right swipe. It's great
Yes
And I get that people I get that the downside of it is if you have a bunch of them in
spaces, if you have a bunch of spaces, each with their own app, you may be swiping for
a while before you find the one you want.
I do agree that that could be better.
But if I just have a couple things, like VS Code is in there, Mail is in there, then I've
got like two, then I've only got to swipe four times max or three times max for that
scenario and it's great.
It's just super great.
And because I have the MacBook Pro now, when I'm using it as a laptop, it's ready.
When I'm at my desk I've got the trackpad here, it's ready.
I agree with you that for me Rectangle Pro makes the Mac, makes my Mac use and my Windows
use very functionally equivalent.
The keystrokes are different, but that's fine, they're very simple.
And I keep forgetting about the zones that you're talking about where you pull the window
and then it snaps, it does its thing.
I use the keyboard shortcuts for the stuff that I do the most often.
And the things that I do the most often are maximize this window, make this window take
up the top quarter of the screen, make this window take up the left half of the screen,
make this window take up the right half of the screen. Those are the things I do the
most. And that very much mirrors my Windows use where I want this window to hop over to
this monitor. I want this window on this monitor. I want this window to take up the full screen.
I want this window to not take up the full screen. So very, very similar. And those things
are built into Windows. If I wanted to do what you do and have my layouts and my zones,
that would require the Pro Tools.
What are they called?
The Pro, what are they called?
The tools?
Microsoft Powertoys.
Powertoys.
Yeah, and I actually installed Powertoys at one point
because I didn't know some of the built-in
windowing shortcuts in Windows.
And then I was showing Mark, a guy I work with,
and he's like, "Oh, but what about the Windows shift
arrow key or the Windows arrow key or the Windows shift
arrow if you want to go a different monitor?"
I tried it and I'm like,
Okay, I'm uninstalling power toys.
So I just installed
Rectangle Pro while you were talking and I
disabled old rectangle on pro rectangle amateur
Yeah, I am now looking at looks like I had pretty much the default configuration
So that's good because I don't need to relearn any shortcuts or anything like that. So that's pretty good. So yeah, that's pretty cool
Here's a here's a power tip about rectangle. That is nice
So if you if you look at the menu bar thing and you click on it
You're looking at all those different options. You'll notice that next display and previous display are there but they don't have keyboard shortcuts
Now I'm sure that you can assign keyboard shortcuts, but here's another trick
let's say you're like me and you've got an Apple Studio display and then your laptop displays off to the left and
Messages let's say opens up on your studio display
But you really want it off on the MacBook Pro display because you're not gonna look at it that often
and you want it visible but out of your way. You don't have to use that. What you
can do is say, "Hey, I want this to use the left half," and you just keep hitting the
left half keyboard shortcut until it moves its way over to the left half on
the second monitor. It'll go to the second monitor. It won't just keep trying
to do it on the first monitor. On the second attempt it'll go, "Hey, he must
want this on the second monitor." And it's kind of weird because it'll go from the
left half on the first monitor to the right half on the second monitor, then to
right half, then to the left half on the second monitor. But it works really nice. So it's like
basically hitting it twice instead of once or whatever. Okay, fair enough. Let's talk a little
more about a couple more things on similar veins to what we're talking about. Okay. In addition to
Moom, which I did not buy, about three years ago, I did buy Witch, W-I-T-C-H, also from ManyTricks,
the same author. And it's essentially a better task manager, like an alt or a command tab replacement.
Oh okay, let's hear about that.
Well, I contacted the developer and I was complaining because recently I've not been
able to use Witch because it just times out. Like I'll hit command tab, it takes a beat or 10 for it
to show up and then I see all of the apps and then it just scrolls through all of them and
slams up against the last one in the task list and then I let go of I can't move like I can't command
shift or move back around so essentially anytime I hit command tab it will always go to the last
program running and so he asked me like what programs are you running and do you have a lot
of windows open so I took a screenshot of everything and I was like yep well here's a
simple list of, you know, like all this stuff. And the response was to the tune of, yeah, you're using
a lot of apps that use a lot of resources. So we can't really handle that. I'll fix that in version
five, but that's down the road. But he did get this three years later, he offered to refund my purchase.
After three years of trying to solve your problem?
Well, I only reported it this week.
And after three years of trying to learn Swift UI? Oh, okay. Nevermind. Sorry.
So...
Rob, if you're listening, Scott's the one being a jerk to you, not me.
I'm not being a jerk to you.
I'm just asking questions.
I did not take him up on the offer.
I wrote him back and I said, "No, I've gotten value for your program."
It was like nine bucks again or something.
I was like, "No, I got value from it."
Oh, for sure.
And not only that, you bothered him for at least $9 worth of support.
Absolutely.
You know?
said there's another program that I used also called share mouse. Never share your mouse with
another person. Never share your mouse, but I do share it with another computer. Now I had for a
long time would have multiple desktops or laptops on my desktop, my physical desktop. And I was using
a program called synergy back in the day. This is like more than 10 years ago. And then synergy was,
it was an open source product, it was free, blah, blah, blah. It was great. And then the author
wanted to, you know, like take a commercial and I guess there's still a free version,
but there's a commercial version. I just didn't like the direction in which he was taking it. And
the communications coming out of him were just like, eh, I don't like that. So I ended up moving
to, um, share mouse, which unlike synergy, I think synergy was Mac Linux and windows. And I believe
I believe ShareMouse is just Mac and Windows,
but I don't have a Linux desktop anymore, so it was fine.
And I was able to pay for support,
and it generally worked pretty well.
But I've recently found out that Barrier
is apparently a Synergy fork, and it is free open source.
So my ShareMouse paid subscription is about to end up,
it's about to expire sometime, I think,
around Christmas or something.
And I'm planning on pivoting over to Barrier at that time.
I'll be testing it between a Windows PC and a Mac.
So barrier instead of share mouse.
Okay.
Instead of Synergy.
So yes.
Is share mouse one word or two?
Yep, one word.
And I believe with like the studly caps, I believe it's a capital M.
Oh no, they've got a space in there.
No, they don't.
Oh, the title on the website looks like, not the title, but the logo on the website looks
like it, but in their copy text they say one word.
Yeah.
Definitely, capital S, capital M. Definitely share mouse.
So overall it works pretty well, but for random, for reasons I don't know of, like it'll randomly
lose the connection on both systems and I just have to restart it on both and then it
just works again.
So what's the one you're going to?
Sorry.
I'm going to try Barrier.
The Barrier Reef?
Uh, no Reef, just Barrier.
And this is Mac utility only?
Nope, this is cross-platform.
I believe it's Mac Windows Linux.
Oh, this is probably this GitHub thing.
Debauchy Barrier.
Debauchery.
So all of these are like,
Sharemouse was like $69 for three years,
I want to say or something.
But the other things, you know, Rectangle,
Moom, Witch, Barrier, they're all like, or even Barrier,
I don't think Barrier has a commercial offering.
You know, we're talking like 10 bucks.
What do you mean for three?
Sharemouse did like three year subscription.
Oh, that's a weird, that's a weird deal, dude.
Yeah, it's a business thing though.
I mean, they give me a discount.
I understand the whole subscription thing,
but what I mean is to do a three year,
okay, I get it, I get what they're doing.
It's just an unusual proposition.
Usually they give you a year and if you pay for the year,
you get a slight discount or maybe not,
but you pay for a year at a time or you can pay monthly,
but three year, that's bold.
You can do, I'm pretty sure you could do a year at a time.
I think I bought three because I was like, you know,
I'll just get a discount.
Oh, okay, gotcha.
So anyway, and ShareMouse does have a free version.
But yeah, right now, ShareMouse Pro,
one year of maintenance is 120 bucks.
Uh-huh.
I'm not gonna pay that.
I wouldn't think not.
Unless I have such a bad experience with Barrier.
Yeah, it looks, yeah.
If I renew it, however, let me find out here.
I'm curious what they're looking to buy.
Register license.
Copy your license key.
Yes, Peter, copy your license key.
Is this 21?
Or is this 22?
'Cause I have one that we're editing
that I haven't published yet.
I thought this was 21.
Yes, you're right.
20 is the one I'm editing.
Jeez.
Yeah, I just, I lose track.
Tell you, it's been a week.
Like I said, I worked an extra 12.
I tell ya, man.
That I didn't expect to.
And I still did my workouts.
I pulled an all-nighter,
then I worked eight more hours that day,
then I still did two hours of workouts that night.
Come on.
Wow.
Wow. I don't make excuses and say I'm not going to work out. Now, yesterday was a day off, but that's because I was way overdue for a day off.
Of fitness, not of work. I did work yesterday. For a lot longer than I expected to, by the way.
Alright. Well, hey. I've been taking it easy and blatantly not doing nearly as much exercise because I've messed up my knee again and I want the damn thing to get better.
Right. I scared myself. A couple days ago, all of a sudden I had a pain right under my knee.
And it felt weird. And now it's completely gone.
I could still run, but when I was walking around I would feel it. It scared me. I thought, "Oh no, I haven't had knee problems in forever."
But then it went away. And I think, you know what I think it was from, literally?
I was doing a treadmill run, and I was tired, and I was bored, and I was running at a decent pace,
and I just started going side to side like a loose skater or something.
I was just kind of running side to side on the treadmill. Just don't know why.
I was listening to some music to get me motivated and I was kind of getting into it.
So I was darting side to side. And I think that lateral action on my knee is probably what did it.
It started like a day and a half after that and then now it's gone.
So you know something I don't really care for that much?
Treadmills?
GitHub.
Oh.
Like when I land on a GitHub project page.
Yep.
I have no freaking clue how to download the program.
Okay, I used to be that way, but what they assume is--
Help me.
Let's click on the Barrier Link, for example.
That's exactly where I went. Where do I go?
You're on a desktop browser, right?
Yep.
So here's why they make this more confusing.
And I didn't figure this out until I learned how to use Git.
Got it.
Once I start using Git, that problem goes away,
because you're just gonna clone the thing,
and you're gonna do it from a command line probably, or a Git client.
Right, but if you are producing software...
I guess, okay, if the intention is to make sure that end users never see your code on
your program, then Git is awesome.
But if you just want to download...
Never see your code.
Yeah, I want to download an executable and install it on two of my machines.
Oh, Git Hub's horrible for that.
That's what I'm talking about.
Like right now, today, I don't want-look, I can't compile anything on my Windows machine.
I don't have a compiler.
I don't want the code for this project.
I just want to install it on my Windows machine.
So for me as an end user right now, I'm like, "WTF, mate?"
Okay, now just because you're downloading it doesn't necessarily mean you're going to
have to compile it.
You can make a release with a binary executable in it.
Right.
And if I could find that easily, I'd be a much happier user.
Okay, well that depends on the project.
Exactly.
In terms of just downloading the Git repo, you click the code button and then you have options.
Do you want to clone this? Do you want to open it with GitHub desktop, which no one ever does?
Or do you want to download a zip file?
As far as whether or not there's a binary available, that's if they create a package.
Exactly.
Right. And this one says no package is published. So that means that you download this source.
There is a dist folder here.
And if I look in the dist folder, I see a Mac OS bundle.
When I scroll down, I see a clean build.bat.
Under bundle there's a barrier dot app. What the heck is Wix?
I don't know, but I don't care. But here's where it is right here. If you go to this bundle
But I do care because I also want to run this on Windows and I see a batch file
I would assume it's that Wix thing.
I don't know what the heck those things are. Barrier dot SLN. Yeah.
I don't know but that sounds like a gap in our knowledge not a gap in his process
Sure, okay. Give the guy the, you know, the benefit of the doubt.
This is my normal experience. When I go to a GitHub project, I feel like an idiot.
Yeah, no, I get it.
There's a clean build.bat file, and it says it uses CMake.
Wix is a window installer XML.
Windows installer XML. Okay.
Wix was the first Microsoft project to be released under an open source license.
Interesting.
So it sounds really old and I don't know what you do once you download that onto your device.
The Mac OS one has an app already built so you don't have to do anything.
Somebody wrote an article that said that it's incredibly easy to install with pre-compiled
binaries for Windows. Okay.
And I'm like, okay, where are they? So I'm just going to put it this way. It
looks to me like the Mac OS one is super easy to do. The Windows one, there's something you
have to understand and I haven't looked to see what the Linux options are under dist. RPM.
So on a page, okay so I did find a page it's DeBarrier, oh it's the wiki page. So you go to
github.com/debocibarrierwiki and there I see packaging status. So I see a bunch of things
there but here's the funny thing I see win get I don't see win doze and I don't see Mac I see tons
of Linux that wiki link is available it shows on everything it's kind of up to the developer to do
something with it yeah exactly so again this is like I said this is just you know he doesn't seem
to be going out of his way to make it easy for a Mac or Windows person to install this without
downloading the code, etc, etc. Oh my god, you have to install... that's because this project
requires a bunch of stuff that I don't want on my computer. You have to install Qt for Windows.
I don't want that. I hell as much don't want that on my Mac. I would never do this.
Dependency hell. Right. Now the nice thing about with Mac is you can install those dependencies
with Homebrew. Right. If you want them in the first place. If you want them. I don't want them.
I don't know why I have such a barrier against QT, but it just seems like one of those things that all the apps that want it make me mad.
And so, and I don't want QT. It's an old, it's an outmoded, look, I have a GUI already, let me use it!
Mm-hmm.
So.
Ahh, so maybe I'm not gonna, I don't know, though, 120 bucks.
Oh, and that, that seems to be my renewal price too, for ShareMouse, is $120 per year.
That seems high.
Peter, I just want to say something.
First of all, keep looking for other options.
Secondly, I am looking.
There is a reason this thing is called "barrier."
They throw up so many barriers to entry that it makes you furious that you even thought
of using it, and it makes you furious that they even thought of you using it.
Uh huh.
Yeah, this is not.
I wouldn't do this one, that's for sure.
I might have to though, I don't know man.
I don't know, I guess I have to figure how QT-averse am I.
Very, it should be the correct answer.
And here's the other thing, Peter,
how often are you actually gonna need this anymore?
I use it fairly frequently.
I definitely, so on my main, my main work setup now is
I have a computer off to my left with a secondary display.
That's strictly for the hospital.
It is air gapped, it's completely separate.
It's not part of this equation.
The rest of it, I have my MacBook Air primary display,
and then I have my big widescreen connected to it.
So I have those two.
Off to the right, I have another Windows laptop,
17 inch or 16 inch, 15 inch, I don't even remember, big.
How many computers are we up to now?
Three, is that the third one?
Three, yes.
That's the one I use the sharing with.
My Logitech MX70 or whatever it is, don't know.
It's got a button here
and it's got frequencies one, two, and three.
Now I haven't done this,
but I think that by pairing at a certain frequency,
which you can do with a specific computer.
You could pair at the different frequency settings
on each of your computers,
and all you have to do is press that button once
to transfer it to the other computer.
But what about the keyboard?
Oh, you didn't say anything about a keyboard, Peter.
Yeah, this is KVM sharing, is what we're doing.
We're sharing the keyboard, the video,
and the mouse switching.
You just said mouse.
So I'm looking at another one
called Mouse Without Borders, but it's Windows only.
Mouse Without Borders. Multiplicity.
It has a normal practice that it practices
for like 50 years, and then once every 10 years,
maybe it'll go for a year to-
Goes away on sabbatical.
Right, and does the mouse without borders thing.
Yep, exactly.
Yeah, I don't know.
So it looks like Barrier, Synergy, and ShareMouse are like,
that's all I'm finding right now
that's actually cross-platform compatible.
Synergy Virtual KVM. Yes. We didn't talk about that one did we? Did you mention? No that was the
one that I used and then I said the developer started and you know like took it in a direction
I wasn't really caring for. What do you mean it became a porn site? No he just like like I was
getting he wanted to charge for it it wasn't clear why I would want to do that and then all of a
sudden I was getting like pictures of like hey look here's our new office and there was a picture
of two people sitting at a desk and I'm like, you want me to pay so you can have two people
sitting at a desk?
Yeah, he's got employees, you dummy.
When to stick with hardware?
If you need to connect one monitor to multiple computers, you'll still need a traditional
KVM.
Yeah, that's not what I'm looking for.
Because I like to share, like, I don't like my hands on one keyboard and mouse.
Yes, yeah, and you can turn your head.
Yep, exactly.
Anyway.
Okay, so I'm clicking on Synergies by now.
I see $29 lifetime download access.
That's not that bad.
29 for lifetime is not that bad.
However, here's the other thing too.
Back when I was complaining about it,
the reason I was complaining was like,
there were a number of bugs that I had submitted.
And instead of like seeing any progress
on the bug fixing front, I was seeing like,
we just bought an office kind of thing.
So, so I was not, yeah.
So that's when I switched over to,
I believe to ShareMouse.
And that was maybe, I don't know what the timeline is.
That might be why ShareMouse or why barrier spun up.
It might've been in, because it is a fork of Synergy.
Is it?
So does Synergy have QT in it?
I don't know.
Well, if it does, I doubt it.
Maybe it does.
Wouldn't surprise me.
Welcome to World Class Productivity.
Fortune 500 companies and over 2 million customers
rely on Synergy every day, Peter,
including Pixar and Apple,
two companies that you may have heard of.
Huh.
There's a Scott with one T that gave a good review to it.
I can't trust him because he's got,
he doesn't have the right number of Ts.
Skeet.
Skeeter, mosquito.
Yeah. Mosquito loves it.
Yeah. So I'm kinda, yeah, I'm kinda torn here.
I don't know.
Peter, have you heard the good news about hardware KVMs?
No, what are they?
Don't know.
But, and here's the other thing,
I don't know if there are any KVMs modern enough
to allow you to use Bluetooth devices with them.
I'm sure there must be some adapters you can plug into them,
but I never tried.
No, I do have a hardware KVM on my desktop.
I haven't really used it though,
since I had just two Windows machines on my desktop.
And that's where I would switch between like hospital one
and non-hospital one.
Yeah.
So anyway.
You know, some people have a day phone and a night phone.
You've got a hospital computer and a non-hospital computer.
Makes perfect sense.
All right.
Well, on that note, we should wrap this puppy up,
Put a bow in it, et cetera, et cetera.
Stick a fork in it, blah, blah, blah.
Do the whole thing.
Push the big red KVM button.
Big red KVM button.
Counting it, why don't you count us down
and then we'll push the button.
Three.
I'm starting at three, is that okay?
Click.